准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流  严禁用于商业用途
裤头村里  正是星期天的早晨
It is Sunday morning in Bikini Bottom
章鱼哥练竖笛的时间就要到了
and it is about time
for Squidward to practice his clarinet
所以快把你的耳塞准备好吧
So get your ear plugs ready
我该给裤头村来点真正的音乐了
I think I'll treat Bikini Bottom to some real music
早上好  章鱼哥
Good morning, Squidward
要去捉水母吗
Wanna go jellyfishing?
太棒了
Great
我们马上就到
We'll be right over
我还在想是谁呢
I wonder who that could be
准备好出发了吗
Ready to go?
不对  我没准备好
No, I'm not ready to go
他不想跟我们玩
He doesn't wanna play with us
才不呢  派大星
No, Patrick
只是没准备好而已
he's just not ready
现在好没
Ready now?
没好
No
那现在呢
How about now?
没好
No
现在呢
Now?
没好
No
现在呢
Now?
没好
No
那现在呢
How about now?
没好
No
现在呢
Now?
没好
No
现在呢
Now?
没好
No
现在呢
Now?
没好
No
现在呢
Now?
没好
No
干嘛
What?
准备好了吗
Ready yet?
我没有准备好
No, I'm not ready
这辈子都准备不好
I'll never be ready
还不明白我意思吗
Don't you get it?
当然明白啊
Sure we do
什么
What?
好没
Ready?
滚出去
Out
哎哟喂
Sheesh
你今天不是该去上班的吗  海绵宝宝
Shouldn't you be at work today, SpongeBob?
我是想今天上班的
I'd love to be at work today
可今天星期天
But it's Sunday
蟹堡王关门
The Krusty Krab is closed
等会啊
Hold on a second
我马上出来
I'll be right out
蟹堡王
有人吗
Hello?
终于孤独一人了
Alone at last
章鱼哥
Squidward
好吧  他不在这
Well, he's not here
我敢赌他等不及先到水母田去了
I'll bet that eager-beaver's
already down at Jellyfish Fields
他们终于走了
They're finally gone
怎么
What the...?
锁上了
Locked?
不好
Oh no
好吧
Oh, well
总有人会发现我不见了  然后来找我
Someone will realize I'm gone and come looking for me
我就马上可以出去了
I'll be out of here in no time
两千年后
我的蟹黄堡啊
Holy Krabby Patties
有只被冻住的头足类动物
A frozen cephalopod
我就马上可以出去了
I'll be out of here in no time
你好  原始生物
Greetings, primitive
海
Sp...
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
是你吗
Is that you?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
不
No
我是机器宝宝
I am SpongeTron
欢迎来到未来
Welcome to the future
说什么
What?
欢迎来到未来
Welcome to the future
未来
The future
好  好吧
O-okay
这是怎么了这
What's going on here?
怎么所有东西都是
Why is everything
镀了铬的
chrome?
未来所有东西都镀上了金属铬
Everything is chrome in the future
什
Wha...?
老天爷啊
Oh, my...
根本不可能
Impossible
他在说谎
He's lying
他还真没说错
He's right
我当然是对的  章鱼哥
Of course I'm right, Squidward
问问我的复制体
Just ask my clones
机器宝宝XYZ吧
SpongeTrons X, Y, and Z
其他的字母也在这是吧
Are the other letters of the alphabet involved here?
当然了
Sure
总共有486个
All 486 of them
未来
Future
谢谢了
Thanks
给我听好
Now listen
都听清楚
All of you
我不属于这里
I don't belong here
这就是一可怕的错误
This is all a horrible mistake
求你们了
Please
好歹也想想办法吧
We've got to do something
捉水母
Jellyfishing
是不是有人说了  捉水母
Did somebody say, "jellyfishing"?
嗨  派大双
Hi, PatTron
听我说好了
Just listen to me
我不应该在这里的
I'm not supposed to be here
我得回到我自己的时空去
I've gotta get home to my own time period
我必须要走
I've gotta go
那你怎么不早说
Well, why didn't you just ask?
时间机器就在走廊尽头左手边
The time machine is down the hall, to the left
啊对
Oh, yeah
那个是开罐器
That one's the can opener
走右边的试试看
But try the one on the right
要是让我来装修  才不选这种丑内饰
Well, I wouldn't have chosen this interior
这什么
What's this?
未来
过去
既然未来有海绵宝宝
Well, if SpongeBob exists in the future
我最好要去
I'd better go to
过去
the past
好原始
Primitive
有点远古世界的魅力
Has sort of an old-world charm
我看这时候怕是还没有发明礼貌
I guess this is before manners were invented
至少没有海绵小鬼的影子
Well, at least there's no sign of SpongeBrat
现在总算可以跟我竖笛孤独在一起了
Maybe now I can finally be alone with my clarinet
什么
What?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
别过来
Stay back
不用了
No thanks
你好啊
Hi there
那个  我最好马上走开
Well, I better be going now
对  这是我胳膊
Yes, that's my arm
真是亲热
That's sweet
干嘛  你现在要洗澡除跳蚤了吗
What, is it time for your flea bath now?
看啊  就一小水母而已
Look, it's just a little jellyfish
好吧  我要走开了
Well, I'm going away now
这有个荫凉的风水宝地
Here's a nice, shady spot
还离那些傻子远远的
away from those fools
你们这些白痴在搞什么
What are you simpletons doing?
你们应该要捉住这玩意的
You're supposed to catch these things
而不是拿这玩意来自虐
not torture yourself with them
遮羞布拿来
Give me those loincloths
真不敢相信
I can't believe it
这样差不多就能万事顺利了
This oughta make things go a little smoother
把那些给我
Give me those things
你们应该要这样子捉住那玩意
You're supposed to catch them, like this
这个叫做捉水母
It's called jellyfishing
终于啊
Finally
让我离开这
Get me outta here
未来
空
废物
Loser
他不在这
He's not here
没有海绵宝宝了
No more SpongeBob
没有了
No more
我终于有地方可以一个人
I may finally have found a place where I can be all
孤独
alone
Alone
孤独
我得离开这
I gotta get outta of here
时间机器在哪
Where's the time machine?
一切都在哪
Where's anything?
在哪
Where?
我要回家
I wanna go home
我想念裤头村
I miss Bikini Bottom
我想念复活节岛人像屋
I miss my Easter Island head
我连海绵宝宝都很想念
I even miss SpongeBob
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
派大星
Patrick
嗨  章鱼哥
Hi, Squidward
我回来了
I'm back
真不敢相信
I can't believe this
我我  我在太空里
I-I-I was in space
然  然后去了未来
a-and I went to the future
再  再然后去了过去
and-and then I went to the past
又又进  进到了世界尽头里
and-and then-then I was nowhere
但是现在我回来了
but now I'm back
并  并且
and-and
你们怕是不知道我见到你们有多开心
you don't know how happy I am to see you guys
意思是不是你要去
Does this mean you wanna go
捉水母了
Jellyfishing?
不
No
到底哪个傻子发明的那游戏
Who's the barnacle head
who invented that game anyway?
你发明的  章鱼哥
You are, Squidward
我要回去了
I'm going back
空手道
分镜总监
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
抱歉  菠萝屋
Sorry, pineapple house
还以为你是别的什么人
I thought you were someone else
真是个美好的工作日
What a great day at work
好啊
Yeah
我知道你在那后头  珊迪
I know you're back there, Sandy
我还知道没人能躲得过我海绵
And I also know that nobody can hide from Sponge
宝宝
Bob
我逮到你了
I got you now
好吧
Well
看来没危险了
I guess the coast is clear
对啊  购物可真是怪
Yeah, shopping's weird
你有没有进过海产品区说
Did you ever go into the seafood aisle and say
谁才吃这玩意
Who eats this stuff?
我好爱这节目
I love this show
我也好爱
Me too
等会啊
Just a second
安全第一
Safety first
现在是
And now
旋转术
spin technique
双重反手松鼠结
Double overhand squirrel knot
我明天还会回来找你的  海绵宝宝
I'm gonna get you tomorrow, SpongeBob
那可未必
That'll be the day
喂
Hello?
你想得美  海绵呆头
Nice try, SpongeBrain
便宜货超市
海草哥
我可真傻
Silly me
嘿  珊迪
Hey, Sandy
有没有听过松鼠跟铁罐的笑话
Have you ever heard the one
about the squirrel and the tin cans?
应该没听过
I don't think so
是这样讲的
Well, it goes like this
等会  我忘了笑点了
Wait, I forgot the punch line
暴  击
想起来了
Oh, yeah
特价
是不是很好笑啊
That's a good one, isn't it?
好美丽的一天
What a beautiful day
美丽的天空
Beautiful sky
美丽的植物
Beautiful plants
植物好
Hi plants
美丽的
Beautiful
罐头堆
pile of cans?
珊迪  这可是你最烂的伪装了
Sandy, that is your worst disguise yet
才不是  海绵宝宝
No it's not, SpongeBob
这个才是
This is
准备好被我无情痛扁很久很久吧
Now, prepare for a long, merciless whooping
火山辣酱
我的最爱
My favorite
凭借调皮捣蛋之力
By the powers of naughtiness
我命令这滴特制的辣酱
I command this particular drop of hot sauce
变得非常
to be really
非常
really
辣
hot
珊迪  等等
Sandy, wait
你赢了
Victory is yours
我就知道你会想通的  海绵宝宝
I knew you'd come to your senses, SpongeBob
整人玩具
可恶
Curses
蟹堡王
要多加奶酪
With extra cheese
此处点餐
打包外带
To go
三份蟹黄堡
Three patties
四份生蚝壳
four large oyster skins
动作快点  海绵宝宝
on the double, SpongeBob
是吗
Oh yeah
逮到你了
Gotcha
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
什么
What?
我要假装无事发生
I'm going to pretend that didn't happen
要么做饭要么走人  海绵宝宝
Now fill these orders or leave, SpongeBob
今天生意忙的很
We're very busy today
上菜了
Order up
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你是要
Now are you gonna
章鱼哥
Squidward
我刚在办公室查账  然后呢
I was going through some records back in me office and
你可终于有假发了
So, you got the hairpiece after all
我的腿
My leg
以为你可以在我上班时偷袭我是吧
Thought you could sneak up on me at work, did ya?
想得美
Well, you can't
因为我敏捷
'Cause I'm fast
我狠
I'm mean
还可以这样
and I can do this
教训了她一顿可真是好
Took care of her, yes I did
老板好
Ahoy, sir
那是怎么回事
What was that?
可是老板
But, sir
她偷袭我
She snuck up on me
擅闯了我自己的道场
In my own dojo
你是不是换新的过敏药吃了  小子
Are you on some new allergy medication, boy?
不是的  老板
No, sir
练空手道而已
Just practicing my karate, sir
也可以说成是空手道
Or kara-tay, as some call it
[ kara-tay：karate的不同读法 ]
空手道
Kara-tay?
你应该要给我练赚钱道的
You should be making me money-ay
用锅铲道来练
With your spatu-lae
现在给我回去干活
Now get back to work
遵命老板
Aye aye, capi-tay
假发不错章鱼哥
Nice hairpiece, Squidward
蟹堡王
海绵宝宝  你拖过卫生间地板了吗
SpongeBob, did you get those bathrooms mopped yet?
拖过了大姐
Yes, ma'am
我是说大哥
I mean, sir
我是说老板
I mean, boss
我是说全权大臣
I mean, poobah
去拖
Go
珊迪
Sandy
不准这样了
No more
可是蟹老板
But, Mr. Krabs
不准再搞空手道了  小子
No more of this karate stuff, lad
再做就开除你
Or you're fired
开除
Fired?
蟹堡王
不准再搞空手道了
No more karate?
我要怎么跟珊迪解释
How am I gonna tell Sandy?
珊迪等等
Sandy, wait
我不可以了
I can't
蟹老板说我不能搞空手道了
Mr. Krabs said I have to give up karate
真的吗  海绵宝宝
Sure, SpongeBob
别别
No, no
真的  珊迪
Really, Sandy
别弄了
Stop
我才不会上当的  海绵宝宝
I'm not falling for it, SpongeBob
别弄了  真的
No, really
求你别这样了
Please, stop
搞什么
What the?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
我刚刚跟你讲什么了  小子
What did I just get through telling ye, lad?
可是我
But I
她
She
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你被开除了
You're fired
开除了
Fired?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
等等
Wait
蟹老板  不是他的错
Mr. Krabs, it's not his fault
是
It's
是我的错
it's mine
他本来要告诉我
He tried to tell me
可我
but I
我没有听
I wouldn't listen
再给他一次机会吧  求你了
Give him another chance, please?
好了  小子
All right, me boy
我再给你一次机会
I'll give you a second chance
不准再弄空手道了
But no more karate
那会毒害你的精神
It's poisoning your mind
这些哺乳动物啊
Mammals
真见鬼
Aww, shoot
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我早该相信你的
I guess you ain't fibbing
反正空手道就要过时了
That game was getting old anyway
已经不好玩了
It's not fun anymore
我意思是
I mean
这有什么
what's so fun about
好玩的
this?
没
Nothing
那根本就没什么好玩的
Nothing is fun about that at all
我们是可以找到至少有
We can find something to do that's at least
九倍好玩的东西的
nine times as fun
真可以吗
We can?
我说的是
I mean
当然可以了
sure we can
好啊
Yeah
比如说我们可以
Like we can
可以挤东西
We can squeeze things
到底有多好玩呢
How much fun was that?
差不多有点了
Almost some
有了
I know
我们可以装成植物
We can act like plants
光合作用
Photosynthesis
要去公园吗
Wanna go to the park?
空手道可真是笨
Karate sure is dumb
你说的可真是对
Yeah, you can say that again
我连想到空手道都觉得笨
I feel dumb just thinking about it
我好笨
I'm stupid
我爱空手道
I like karate
你爱什么
You like what?
反正不是空手道
Not karate
我连那玩意是什么都不知道
I don't even know what that is
我也是
Me, too
我什么都不知道
I don't know what anything is
其实
In fact
等会  那听起来好像是
For a second, that sounded like
空手道
Karate?
现在就来吗
Right now?
我说的是  才不来
I mean, no
空手道是个什么玩意
What is this karate?
你三明治上要加什么
What do you want on your sandwich?
空手道
Karate
你说什么了
What did you say?
芥末酱
Mustard
我三明治上要加芥末酱
I want mustard on my sandwich
开始吧
There we go
你要多少的藤壶块
How many slices of barnacle loaf do you want?
一块
One
一块就行
Just one
一块给你
One for you
一块给我
And one for me
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
就再来一块吧
Maybe just one more
我有点饿了
I'm kinda hungry
可以啊  珊迪
Sure thing, Sandy
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
怎么了
Yeah?
你觉得
Do you think
你觉得我可以切这块吗
Do you think I could cut this one?
可以
Sure
谢谢了
Thanks
切够了吗
Is that enough?
再切一块吧
Maybe just one more
两块也行
Or two
三块也行
Or three
十块也行
Or ten
十块
Ten
好  就十块
Yes, ten
因为我们真的好饿
Because we're really hungry
好
Right
该放面包了
Time for buns
来点番茄怎么样
How about some tomatoes?
我来切奶酪
And I'll cut the cheese
还要再切什么
And, what else should we slice?
再切面包
More buns
还有生菜
And lettuce
做三明治可真是好玩
Making sandwiches sure is fun
对吧  珊迪
Right, Sandy
对吧
Right?
我看我现在要吃个三明治了
I guess I'll eat one now
你要被我剁碎了
You're mince meat
你做梦
In your dreams
真是见鬼了
What the barnacle
你觉得蟹老板搞过空手道吗
Do you think Mr. Krabs ever does karate?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
蟹老板  近来可好
Mr. Krabs, how's it going?
今天很美好吧
Nice day, huh?
好吧  蟹老板
Alright, Mr. Krabs
你抓了我个现行
You caught me
可你知道吗
But you know what?
我就是忍不住
I just can't help myself
你开除我吧
You're just gonna have to fire me
开除你
Fire ya?
我想到了别的办法
I've got something else in mind
蟹堡王
我爱空手道
I love karate
I love kara-tay
我爱赚钱道
I love money-ay
我恨你们仨
I hate all of you